<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>AutomationWhiz</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 14:50:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Robotic Process Automation vs. Machine Learning</title>
		<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/rpa-vs-machine-learning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 08:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.automation-whiz.com/?p=33081</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span> We live in a time when technologies are constantly evolving, and there is always a need for efficient and fast-moving tech-enabled solutions. It is well-known that Robotic Process Automation (RPA) and Machine learning (ML) are currently essential technologies and the most talked-about technologies of this decade. Today, these technologies drive growth and help businesses by&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/rpa-vs-machine-learning/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Robotic Process Automation vs. Machine Learning</span></a></p>
The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/rpa-vs-machine-learning/">Robotic Process Automation vs. Machine Learning</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>We live in a time when technologies are constantly evolving, and there is always a need for efficient and fast-moving tech-enabled solutions. It is well-known that Robotic Process Automation (RPA) and Machine learning (ML) are currently essential technologies and the most talked-about technologies of this decade.</p>



<p>Today, these technologies drive growth and help businesses by optimizing costs incurred to manage people, processes and increase efficiencies of organizations. Not only this, but automation makes the mundane and complex processes easier and faster to increase the productivity of an organization.</p>



<p>The question is how different these technologies are from one another.</p>



<h2>Defining Robotic Process Automation &amp; Machine Learning</h2>



<p>RPA or RPA bots can be defined as digital workers in business processes. In contrast, machine learning is the application of intelligence, which focuses on developing computer programs that can understand data and use it to learn for themselves to perform specific tasks better.</p>



<p>RPA bot automates, whereas machine learning processes are guided by lessons learned by following patterns after understanding existing data sets.</p>



<p>The difference between&nbsp;<a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/a-step-by-step-process-to-rpa-implementation-with-best-practices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RPA</a>&nbsp;and machine learning is that RPA doesn’t have any built-in intelligence, while machine learning works within a predefined knowledge area. RPA works as per the predefined rules whereas machine learning is structured to use historical data to make predictions.</p>



<h2>The difference between Machine learning &amp; Robotic Automation Process</h2>



<p>Businesses aim to attain a large share of the market. It can become possible only when the processes streamline the workflow, reduce wastage, and adopt an automated format. The outcomes are better productivity, real-time insights, there is a probability of more customers increasing per year, and eventually, more revenue per work cycle.</p>



<p>These technologies can help gain better control over processes and streamline them in an optimized time and at a reduced cost. Before using these technologies, it is crucial to understand the difference:</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img width="502" height="434" src="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Machine-learning-and-Robotic-Automation-Process.png" alt="" class="wp-image-33116" srcset="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Machine-learning-and-Robotic-Automation-Process.png 502w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Machine-learning-and-Robotic-Automation-Process-300x259.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 502px) 100vw, 502px" /></figure></div>


<h2>How these technologies impact businesses</h2>



<p>The COVID-19 has shifted the focus of businesses towards rapid digital transformation and utilize smart systems to enhance their operational efficiency and to stay ahead in the ever-evolving market landscape while optimizing their resources &amp; costs like never before, this has increased the willingness of firms to invest in automation and AI/ML technologies.</p>



<p>The market size of RPA stood at USD 1.29 billion in 2020, and the global robotic process automation (RPA) market size is estimated to reach USD 7.64 billion in 2028 as per a report titled “<a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/05/06/2224527/0/en/Robotic-Process-Automation-RPA-Market-Reached-USD-7-46-Billion-in-2028-Surging-Advancements-in-Machine-Learning-ML-and-Artificial-Intelligence-AI-to-Boost-Growth-Fortune-Business-I.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Robotic Process Automation Market Size, Share &amp; COVID-19 Impact Analysis</a>“. The Machine Learning enabled solutions are also being adopted extensively. It&nbsp;<a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/machine-learning-market-size-to-reach-96-7-billion-by-2025--based-on-rising-usage-of-data-science--ai-technologies-for-driving-business-processes--million-insights-301262601.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">accounted for USD 6.9 billion in 2018 and is anticipated to value USD 96.7 billion</a>&nbsp;until 2025.</p>



<p>RPA and AI/ML technologies will impact almost every sector in the years ahead. Tech-enabled solutions such as Robotic Process Automation bots assist in building a digital workforce, and strategic automation and technology like hyper-automation can combine and yield seamless process management, as well as Intelligent technologies like machine learning, will support the workforce to streamline workflows and processes.</p>



<p>In the end, we can conclude that Robotic Process Automation or RPA bots are the digital workers for an organization; Machine Learning is best utilized to speed up the data processing capabilities for better optimization of the three – Processes, Resources, and Costs. Both technologies are equally important for driving the growth of the organization.</p>



<p>Cygnet Infotech, in recent years, has assisted many clients with high-velocity data by using emerging technologies like AI/ML and through RPA bot’s implementation. We help automate business processes and ease implementation of various manual tasks through our offerings &amp; expertise for clients in industries such as BFSI, Logistics, Real estate, and others. For example, the Data management accuracy of a giant Pharma client was increased by 99% through our Automation Platform, which helped in reducing the overall manual data processing time from 5 days to 10-15 mins. </p>



<p></p>The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/rpa-vs-machine-learning/">Robotic Process Automation vs. Machine Learning</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>RPA in Supply chain and Logistics</title>
		<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/rpa-in-supply-chain-and-logistics/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.automation-whiz.com/?p=33092</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">4</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span> Supply chain and logistics involve numerous mundane tasks like data entry, billing, collections, order processing, internal reporting, etc.&#160;Supply chain management deals with managing all these processes involved in the distribution of products to increase revenue by enhancing sales productivity, cutting down costs, and minimizing storage. AI and RPA are the technologies that can help managers&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/rpa-in-supply-chain-and-logistics/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">RPA in Supply chain and Logistics</span></a></p>
The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/rpa-in-supply-chain-and-logistics/">RPA in Supply chain and Logistics</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">4</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>Supply chain and logistics involve numerous mundane tasks like data entry, billing, collections, order processing, internal reporting, etc.&nbsp;Supply chain management deals with managing all these processes involved in the distribution of products to increase revenue by enhancing sales productivity, cutting down costs, and minimizing storage. AI and RPA are the technologies that can help managers achieve these goals.</p>



<h2>Why RPA in Supply Chain and Logistics?</h2>



<p>Supply chain and logistics involve many processes that are manual and time-consuming. Some of the challenges that the supply chain and logistics personnel face on a daily basis are:</p>



<ul><li>Human errors caused due to manual process</li><li>Inefficient work processes because of repeated, mundane activities</li><li>Less productivity, more time taken to accomplish any task</li><li>Legacy systems that are not capable of transferring data to other systems</li></ul>



<p>All these challenges can be eliminated with the help of intelligent bots and AI. The list of challenges that can be addressed with the use of RPA is exhaustive. RPA can be used to automate the processes across the supply chain operations like:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cygnet-infotech.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/RPA-in-Supply-Chain-and-Logistics.png" alt="RPA in Supply Chain and Logistics" class="wp-image-16092"/></figure>



<h3>Order and payment processes</h3>



<p>The order process is the core of the order fulfillment workflow. It deals with everything from when the order is placed and received by the customer. RPA can be used to automate the processing of the desired amount by the payment gateways and sending text and emailing to the customers regarding the confirmation of order placement.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Email automation</strong>:&nbsp;Bots can be deployed to make the communication of the shipment status clear to the customers, leading to a smooth experience and an increase in customer satisfaction.</p>



<h3>Transportation &amp; Logistics Management</h3>



<p><strong>Automate exporter’s information</strong>: A bot can be deployed to pull data from an excel file, feeds the data into the website, and extract available information to be shared with dedicated stakeholders.</p>



<p><strong>Bill of Entry for CHA – Information extraction</strong>:&nbsp;Bots can be deployed to scan folders, read the Bill of Entry documents in standard PDF format, extract data of items, validate information like HSN, and generate the report in CSV format.</p>



<p><strong>Distance Calculation for Bill of Entry</strong>: A bot can be deployed to fetch distance between two geographical points based on the pin code provided. This helps in identifying the exact distance between source and destination and helps organizations save cost on additional cost</p>



<ol type="1"><li>Can help you know the cost of shipment (travel cost/fuel)</li><li>Cost of tolls</li><li>know the time to travel (if integrated with google maps)</li></ol>



<p><strong>Calculating freight cost</strong>: RPA helps with automatically fetching the details from the railway freight website and passing the information in CSV format to the respective teams.</p>



<p><strong>Shipment tracking</strong>: RPA helps in finding shipment tracking information like location, status from logistics operator portals and inform respective teams</p>



<h3>Invoicing</h3>



<p><strong>Invoice information extraction</strong>: Bots can be deployed to scan folders, read the Invoices, extract required data of the items, and generate the report in CSV format.</p>



<p><strong>Invoice Validation, Reconciliation &amp; Processing in the import lifecycle</strong>: RPA can be very helpful in reconciling the data based on customs declaration numbers. It also helps validate the invoices by preparing reports, highlighting the discrepancy in the following three buckets:</p>



<ul><li>Transactions present in ERP &amp; customs portal</li><li>Transactions present in ERP but not in a customs portal</li><li>Transactions present in the customs portal but not in ERP</li></ul>



<h3>Inventory management and Fulfillment process</h3>



<p>RPA systems can detect patterns from the past data on inventory and help reorder and maintain stock as per the market’s requirements. Bots can also be deployed to automate the checking of items in the warehouse, generate and validate delivery orders, send acknowledgment mails to respective parties, and fill details in ERP.</p>



<h3>Customer Service and Relationship Management</h3>



<p>RPA can be used to automate customer service and relationship management by enhancing customer experience and satisfaction levels:</p>



<ul><li>RPA bots can give instant replies to any question asked by a customer.</li><li>Bots can classify the queries department vise and send them to the respective departments.</li><li>Customer relationship management can be automated by using RPA to perform tasks that are repetitive and voluminous.</li><li>RPA can categorize customer data based on various parameters, which in turn can be used for different purposes.</li></ul>



<h2>Benefits of RPA in Supply Chain and Logistics</h2>



<p><strong>Enhanced speed of work processes</strong>: Personnel involved in the supply chain have many manual processes to carry on daily. Deploying a bot that can do the manual job of data entry, email communication, tracking the shipment, and extracting, sorting, and validating data would speed the work and increase the focus on critical decision-making and result-oriented tasks.</p>



<p><strong>Decrease operational cost</strong>: Since the deployment of bots can increase the speed of operations, organizations can save the cost on human resources while decreasing the pressure on their employees at the same time, thus saving the cost on operations and improving the work efficiency of the personnel. RPA further helps prevent cost by:</p>



<ul><li>Generating reports.</li><li>Alerting about any changes in the estimated time of arrivals.</li><li>Identifying plausible charges related to storage.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Improved data for analysis</strong>:&nbsp;RPA helps in creating appropriate and accurate data. Organizations can deploy bots to go through large quantities of data to segregate valuable data. The accuracy of data extracted or created by a bot improves the quality of analysis, leading to better forecasts and minimized future risks.</p>



<p><strong>Easy reconciliation of data</strong>: One can deploy a bot to compare data with the data present on different websites, PDFs, excels, etc., for generating qualitative and quantitative information that can be used to integrate processes for enhancing the overall performance of the entire supply chain system.</p>



<p><strong>Efficient delivery</strong>: RPA can improve the efficiency of the delivery phase of the supply chain system. Bots can automatically assign delivery to the delivery partners based on the location of products and send information to the customers if the delivery delays, enhancing the customer experience with real-time order updates.</p>



<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>



<p>RPA, along with AI, has eased the life of organizations by performing all the repetitive and mundane tasks without human intervention. It’s not only economical but also efficient and structured. Supply chain managers should strive to <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com//blog/a-step-by-step-process-to-rpa-implementation-with-best-practices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">implement RPA </a>to keep track of logistics and update the inventory. Automation enablers like <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/">AutomationWhiz</a> can help organizations build bots that assist their supply chain journeys and create a smooth supply chain experience.</p>The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/rpa-in-supply-chain-and-logistics/">RPA in Supply chain and Logistics</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A step-by-step process to RPA implementation with best practices [2021 guide]</title>
		<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/a-step-by-step-process-to-rpa-implementation-with-best-practices/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.automation-whiz.com/?p=33102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">8</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span> RPA stands for&#160;Robotic&#160;Process&#160;Automation;&#160;We&#160;all know it. But things that have remained untouched for many users about RPA implementation requirements, practices worth knowing about, and ways to implement RPA in a business-centric manner. So, in this post, we intend to walk you through:&#160; Why businesses need to adopt RPA&#160; What is the feasibility of RPA implementation –&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/a-step-by-step-process-to-rpa-implementation-with-best-practices/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">A step-by-step process to RPA implementation with best practices [2021 guide]</span></a></p>
The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/a-step-by-step-process-to-rpa-implementation-with-best-practices/">A step-by-step process to RPA implementation with best practices [2021 guide]</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">8</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>RPA stands for&nbsp;Robotic&nbsp;Process&nbsp;Automation;&nbsp;We&nbsp;all know it. But things that have remained untouched for many users about RPA implementation requirements, practices worth knowing about, and ways to implement RPA in a business-centric manner. So, in this post, we intend to walk you through:&nbsp;</p>



<ol type="1"><li><a href="#adoptRPA">Why businesses need to adopt RPA</a>&nbsp;</li><li><a href="#RPAImplementation">What is the feasibility of RPA implementation – how soon organizations can deploy it provided they have a clear roadmap</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li><a href="#AdvantagesRPA">Advantages of using RPA</a>&nbsp;</li><li><a href="#rule">Rule based automation and cognitive automation&nbsp;</a></li><li><a href="#processesautomated">Identifying the processes that can be automated&nbsp;</a> </li><li><a href="#Use-case-Identification">Use case Identification – Involving key stakeholders &#8211; develop process profile &#8211; create a workflow diagram</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li><a href="#RPA-pre-post">RPA pre and post Implementation process</a></li><li><a href="#RPAUseCases">RPA Use Cases – Common processes that many organizations are automating include the below&nbsp;&nbsp;</a></li><li><a href="#RPApartner">Choosing the right RPA Implementation Partner&nbsp;</a></li><li>&nbsp;<a href="#RPA-conclusion">Conclusion</a>&nbsp;</li></ol>



<h2 id="adoptRPA">Why businesses need to adopt RPA&nbsp;</h2>



<figure class="wp-container-2 wp-block-gallery-1 wp-block-gallery aligncenter has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="602" height="325" data-id="33105"  src="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/PWC-rpa-guide.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-33105" srcset="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/PWC-rpa-guide.jpg 602w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/PWC-rpa-guide-300x162.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px" /><figcaption><br><br></figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p></p>



<p><strong>RPA can benefit businesses in the following ways:</strong> </p>



<ul><li>Improvement in ROI figures&nbsp;</li><li>Better productivity&nbsp;</li><li>Employee retention&nbsp;</li><li>Zero-error processes&nbsp;</li><li>Intuitive process planning&nbsp;</li><li>AI and ML supported data processing&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>So,&nbsp;let us&nbsp;explore these reasons one by one!&nbsp;</p>



<h4><strong>Improvement in ROI figures</strong>&nbsp;</h4>



<p>Every process is designed keeping returns in mind. RPA is not an exception either. Businesses aim to capture the largest possible chunk of market share. It can become possible only when the processes streamline the workflow, reduce wastage, and adopt an automated format. The final outcomes are better productivity, more orders per year, and eventually, more profits per&nbsp;work cycle.&nbsp;</p>



<h4><strong>Better productivity</strong></h4>



<p>Employees’ time that goes into repetitive processes may be used to better quality jobs with RPA implementation. RPA can perform operations <a href="https://www.niceincontact.com/blog/beginners-guide-to-robotic-process-automation-rpa#:~:text=With%20RPA%2C%20software%20%22robots%22,faster%20and%20with%20no%20errors.&amp;text=This%20is%20because%2C%20like%20human,robot%20has%20a%20finite%20capacity." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">five times faster</a> and with no deviation from pre-fed instructions. Thus, nil error helps complete more process cycles any given workday.&nbsp;</p>



<h4><strong>Employee retention</strong>&nbsp;</h4>



<p>Employees do feel frustrated when they are evaluated based on&nbsp;jobs&nbsp;that&nbsp;do not&nbsp;complement&nbsp;their&nbsp;expertise. Repetitive processes and&nbsp;those&nbsp;which involve only following certain instructions&nbsp;cannot&nbsp;provide&nbsp;any employee job satisfaction. RPA implementation offers employers the correct environment for using the workforce as per their&nbsp;expertise. It reflects the deepened loyalty of the employees to their organizations.&nbsp;</p>



<h4><strong>Zero-error processes</strong>&nbsp;</h4>



<p>RPA implementation can help achieve higher accuracy in rule-based processes. A typical rule-based process flow can be automated&nbsp;up to&nbsp;70-80% with RPA. Since there are no repetitions and rechecks&nbsp;required, the manufacturers can roll out applications in the market faster than in&nbsp;previous&nbsp;instances.&nbsp;</p>



<h4><strong>Intuitive process planning</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</h4>



<p>Planning must have an element of intuition in the processes. In sectors like banking and insurance, RPA supports intuitive processes’ planning. Digitization was introduced with an aim to ease the processes and give quicker services. With the help of intuitive process planning empowered by RPA, the businesses involved in public dealing can give a seamless user experience to the customers.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="RPAImplementation">What is the feasibility of RPA implementation</h2>



<h5 id="RPAImplementation"><strong>How soon organizations can deploy it provided they have a clear roadmap</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</h5>



<p>It is a common experience that any upgrade can be included in the work ecosystem only when it is most easy to do so. RPA implementation exhibits the same requirement.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Quick-to-roll and easily employable by all, the RPA solutions take no more than a couple of weeks to implement. Cygnet Infotech which is designing and delivering RPA solutions makes the following observations as regards to the feasibility of RPA implementation:&nbsp;</p>



<ul type="a"><li>&nbsp;Processes should be repetitive, rule-based and are most likely to get badly affected by manual interventions.&nbsp;</li><li>RPA makes most sense when large batches of entries are to be made. Or the users require processing the same command multiple times with a focus on sticking to compliance on every single instance.&nbsp;</li><li>RPA should make a difference to the way of working of organizations; also, there should be a scope for adopting innovation on a large scale.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Other points to consider while analyzing the feasibility of RPA are:</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Alignment with business goal: RPA implementation proves to be a wise decision when it supports accomplishing business goals faster. Also, it should continue to prove its worth even when the business goals change in accordance with the change in business phase.&nbsp;</li><li>Supportive of improvement in product offering: Like any technological enhancement, RPA implementation should help in improving the quality of product offering and strategy.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Ease of method implementation: The RPA implementation can become feasible when it does not require too intrinsic procedures or complex technological training. Anything possible to learn and implement becomes easy to include in the work ecosystem, RPAs are designed keeping this factor in mind. Good News is that RPA does not require any programming knowledge (Lacity&nbsp;et al., 2016)&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>To sum up,</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Businesses are familiar with Business Process Re-engineering. And, feel that this is it. The feasibility of RPA becomes easy to achieve and proves to be a practical process when it is seen as an activity that complements the benefits of BPR. If it is looked upon as a replacement for BPR, the initial reaction may be that of not adopting the process.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-container-4 wp-block-gallery-3 wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="602" height="325" data-id="33109"  src="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Avg-speed-to-RPA-dev.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-33109" srcset="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Avg-speed-to-RPA-dev.jpg 602w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Avg-speed-to-RPA-dev-300x162.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px" /></figure>
</figure>



<h2 id="AdvantagesRPA">Advantages of using RPA&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Businesses felt the need to supplement BPR with something more quick, seamless, advanced, and feasible. RPAs characteristically fulfill all these criteria. Of the various advantages, the biggest plus is that the RPA helps reduce human efforts and does not require too many changes in the existing process framework.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The other commendable advantages of implementing RPA are:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>Human behavior mimicking: Human-like interactions become possible to achieve between the machines and people, and interpersonally too. These interactions are entirely free from the manual errors too.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>For example, in the sectors such as retail and real estate, the RPAs are fed with the questions that form the part of natural interactions between entities internal and external to businesses. The chatbots resolving sales enquiries, and managing customers and visitors in an intuitive tone are classic examples of CRM RPAs.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Better security level: <a href="https://www.edureka.co/blog/rpa-developer-roles-and-responsibilities/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">RPA designers</a> ensure that they are fully accustomed with all security requirements. The RPAs make processes quick but never at the cost of compliance and safety. Best-quality encryptions, in-depth knowledge of all possible sources of security loopholes and automated ways of offering security upgradation solutions ensure that the data or information and processes remain functional within the aegis of required safety policies like data protection, process patenting, etc.&nbsp;</li><li>Heavily reduced process time: The process time is heavily reduced when RPA implementation supports it. With the focus on process clarity, and understanding of cycle repetition requirements, the designers can employ RPAs to bring seamlessness in processes like employee or customer onboarding, automating performance builds, supply chain management, equipment and raw material reordering and several others. Thus, processes are run optimally and the equipment idle time is reduced drastically too. Since process and application logic remains intact, the RPA offers a seamless approach for quickening the processes in complete alignment with anticipated results.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h2 id="rule">Rule-based vs cognitive automation</h2>



<p>As an RPA user, you must know about both rule-based and cognitive automation. The rules-based automation process is designed to reduce complications, remove human error, and to ensure industry-governed procedures. With the help of rules-based RPA models, the implementation experts can provide reliable support for:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Big-sized batch processing in minimal time&nbsp;</li><li>Compliance with the safety and quality norms&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Quicker resolution of queries and fast settlement processes&nbsp;</li><li>Uniform output from manufacturing processes involved in B2B industry&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>In essence, wherever intelligence and decision-making are not required, one can adopt rules-based RPA models and achieve better performance in terms of quality, speed, usability, and compliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Cognitive RPA models take the processes beyond rules-based. The RPAs with cognitive abilities are empowered with tools like AI, Machine Learning, Deep Thinking, Text Analytics, Natural Language Processing, Optical Character Recognition, etc.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, cognitive RPAs work for those areas where intelligence is a prerequisite for better quality outputs.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The&nbsp;following requirements are ought to be fulfilled for implementing cognitive RPAs:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>Teaching chatbots the ways to converse human-like with data mining, etc.&nbsp;</li><li>Capture all situations and use cases where automation can be done. Develop intelligent solutions to supplement those use cases as well.&nbsp;</li><li>Deployment requires strategic planning and prioritizing areas of implementation.&nbsp;</li><li>Testing and performance analysis followed by redesigning and introducing user-centric features.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Rule-based and cognitive automation have a divided patronage. Some experts call cognitive automation the future and have already got the names for it &#8211; hyper-automation, intelligent automation, AI process automation, etc. There is still a chunk of experts that say that rule-based automation is the only practically feasible form of RPA and that cognitive automation is too futuristic. It is believed to be still in its nascent stage and adoption needs a lot of shifts of perspectives and technology upgrades.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="processesautomated">Identifying the processes that can be automated</h2>



<p>Since the implementation of RPA will receive welcome gestures only when the process is simple and effortless, the experts have stipulated that one should go for RPA implementation only when the processes have the following characteristics.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Rule-based:&nbsp;</strong>The process must be based on a specific set of rules. For example, in the insurance claims settlement process, the considerations are constant. Hence, as soon as the specifications are met, the process initiates automatically when RPA is implemented.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>High volume</strong>: RPA implementation serves the needs most correctly when the process to be automated requires handling large volumes of orders concurrently.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Error-Prone</strong>: A minuscule typo or shuffling of digits can cause huge losses especially when money is involved. Hence, RPA should be employed in those cases where erroneous entries need to be avoided.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Speed sensitive:&nbsp;</strong>Customer experience is one of the main objectives of RPA implementation. This experience can be created in a&nbsp;high-quality&nbsp;manner when it carries an element of immediacy. RPAs in customer service or in the form of CRM chatbots can give quick resolution, collect consents for order processing and provide order status instantly. It helps provide customers the assurance they need.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Requiring temporary workers:&nbsp;</strong>Replacing humans with machines works best when the project is not of constant nature. If the staff is required only for a specific&nbsp;time period, businesses can reduce employee expenses by assigning such jobs to automated machines.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;  </p>



<div class="wp-container-8 wp-block-group p-3 py-2 border rounded hover-shadow has-background" style="background-color:#0d3862"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h6 class="has-text-align-center mb-3 has-white-color has-text-color" style="font-size:22px">Start with your Automation journey now</h6>



<div class="wp-container-6 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-5 wp-block-column">
<p class="has-text-align-center fst-italic has-white-color has-text-color" style="font-size:17px">Access our Free BOTs and start automating a bunch of your repetitive processes in a minute</p>
</div>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-7 wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button text-center w-100 cta-bot-store is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-background-color has-text-color has-background" href="https://automationwhiz.store/home" style="color:#0d3862" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <img src="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/AW_Bot.png" title="aw-boat" alt="bot cta">  Bot Store</a></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<h2 id="Use-case-Identification">Use case Identification </h2>



<h5 id="Use-case-Identification"><strong>Involving key stakeholders &#8211; develop process profile &#8211; create a workflow diagram&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;</h5>



<p>To make RPA implementation possible, the experts suggest the following workflow:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Identify the use case where RPA implementation can create maximum impact and provide ease of working.&nbsp;</li><li>Develop RPA user profiles that means process, user authority and their priorities should be defined.&nbsp;</li><li>Develop use cases to understand the process flow, post automation impacts and also input resource needs.&nbsp;</li><li>Prepare a priority plan to select the starting point and the ensuing flow of RPA implementation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Defining institutional protocols is another important process of use case identification. The requirements to define and implement protocols while defining implementation workflow are:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Ensuring that all users have document workflows&nbsp;</li><li>Have at least five processes ready for robotic automation&nbsp;</li><li>Identifying scope for target workflow improvement areas&nbsp;</li><li>Identifying and evaluating all impact metrics’ potential&nbsp;</li></ul>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="355" height="1024" src="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/RPA-Implementation-process-infographic.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-33111" srcset="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/RPA-Implementation-process-infographic.jpg 355w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/RPA-Implementation-process-infographic-104x300.jpg 104w" sizes="(max-width: 355px) 100vw, 355px" /></figure></div>


<h2 id="RPA-pre-post">RPA Pre and Post Implementation Process</h2>



<p>As a part of the pre-and post-implementation process, the RPA experts need to perform some crucial analyses. These points of analysis include (mentioned on the basis of priority attached):</p>



<figure class="wp-container-10 wp-block-gallery-9 wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="917" height="1024" data-id="33112"  src="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/RPA-Pre-and-Post-Implementation-Process-917x1024-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-33112" srcset="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/RPA-Pre-and-Post-Implementation-Process-917x1024-1.jpg 917w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/RPA-Pre-and-Post-Implementation-Process-917x1024-1-269x300.jpg 269w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/RPA-Pre-and-Post-Implementation-Process-917x1024-1-768x858.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 917px) 100vw, 917px" /></figure>
</figure>



<p><strong>From RPA to DPA</strong> &#8211; <a href="https://www.pega.com/system/files/resources/2018-12/from-rpa-to-dpa.pdf?_rid=YToxOntzOjM6Im5pZCI7czo1OiI5MTkyMSI7fQ--&amp;utm_source=google&amp;utm_content=pcrid%7C482227154377%7Cpkw%7Ckwd-302497173824%7Cpmt%7Cb%7Cpdv%7Cc%7C&amp;utm_medium=cpc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pega</a></p>



<h2 id="RPAUseCases">RPA Use Cases</h2>



<p>Every industry now has conditions that are conducive to the successful implementation of RPA. Some of the proven use cases are:&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Quick and easy processing of orders and the fastest possible query resolution.</li><li>Invoice processing: Teach the robots how to read data fields, place values in correct slots and finally feed those with the data files. You can get uncountable invoices processed throughout the day with minimal to nil errors.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Bank Statement Reconciliation: (Extracted from&nbsp;<a href="https://automationedge.com/blogs/the-role-of-rpa-in-streamlining-the-bank-reconciliation-process/#:~:text=Essentially%2C%20an%20RPA%20works%20by,mismatches%20and%20discrepancies%20are%20identified." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">automation edge</a>), this activity is huge and quite critical. All the issues like human-generated data errors, discrepancies of date and time, etc. can cause audit issues and frauds that can even sabotage the image of the brand. RPA enables users to avoid these critical errors and get processes done&nbsp;real&nbsp;quick.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h2 id="RPApartner">Choosing the right RPA Implementation Partner</h2>



<p>While selecting the right RPA implementation partner, the business owners/managers must evaluate the following points:&nbsp;</p>



<p>While selecting the right RPA implementation partner, the business owners &amp; managers must&nbsp;evaluate the following points:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Level of expertise in RPA implementation</li><li>Futuristic approach</li><li>Dedicated client management team</li><li>Expertise in business processes and ability to understand and evaluate the position of RPA in the current infrastructure ecosystem</li><li>Training staff availability to let workers understand and be familiar with the RPA and its role</li><li>Technical expertise and knowledge is important for proper business transformation</li><li>Ask for risk-free costing that is transparent as well for licensing, maintenance, and support</li></ul>



<h2 id="RPA-conclusion">Conclusion</h2>



<p>RPA implementation is one of the best things happening around.&nbsp;Businesses are required to be digitally transformed and they have a lot of opportunities to explore with the correct tools in hand.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, it really depends on the complexity involved in business processes.&nbsp;Along with cost factors, small and medium enterprises may find it difficult to design&nbsp;an ideal RPA journey.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hence, using the RPA implementation partner is a correct and wise decision. They can identify the RPA implementation needs and areas, and help businesses make decisions which are in the best interest of the businesses.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/a-step-by-step-process-to-rpa-implementation-with-best-practices/">A step-by-step process to RPA implementation with best practices [2021 guide]</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The CIO’s take on RPA: Optimize business processes to multiply ROI</title>
		<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/the-cios-take-on-rpa-optimize-business-processes-to-multiply-roi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.automation-whiz.com/?p=33133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span> Let’s be real, speed, precision and transparency are cornerstones for thriving businesses. In order to excel on these benchmarks, it is imperative for businesses to adopt evolving technology solutions – this is where RPA steps in as a technology disruption positively impacting people, processes and technology.  Having said this, lack of understanding around this tech and apprehensions&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/the-cios-take-on-rpa-optimize-business-processes-to-multiply-roi/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The CIO’s take on RPA: Optimize business processes to multiply ROI</span></a></p>
The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/the-cios-take-on-rpa-optimize-business-processes-to-multiply-roi/">The CIO’s take on RPA: Optimize business processes to multiply ROI</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>Let’s be real, speed, precision and transparency are cornerstones for thriving businesses. In order to excel on these benchmarks, it is imperative for businesses to adopt evolving technology solutions – this is where RPA steps in as a technology disruption positively impacting people, processes and technology. </p>



<p>Having said this, lack of understanding around this tech and apprehensions regarding its implementations are restricting businesses to Think RPA to encourage digital transformation within the organization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>RPA can tackle some of the most common business bottlenecks such as:</p>



<ul><li>Automate labor-intensive repetitive tasks</li><li>Extract massive data</li><li>Extend existing business process capabilities</li><li>Deliver superior customer experience</li><li>Help to derive intelligence out of heaps of data</li><li>Enable high quality and non-erroneous data</li><li>Radically reduce lengthy processes</li><li>Maintain high cost of implementation</li></ul>



<p>RPA reduces swivel chair processes and augments human capabilities to focus more on value-added tasks. Organizations are already adopting RPA to disrupt legacy ways of working and discover newer possibilities.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>The active spend on RPA tools was $1 billion in 2019, but has ratchet up to $1.5 billion by 2020, according to Forrester Research, which says that 40 percent of enterprises will operate automation centers and frameworks this year. –&nbsp;<a href="https://go.forrester.com/blogs/predictions-2019-automation-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forrester</a></p></blockquote>



<p>A quick peek on the key RPA trends to caution businesses on why RPA adoption is necessary.</p>



<ol><li>Acceleration of businesses processes and growth with RPA70 percent of business leaders have plans of investing more in the development and implementation of RPA.<strong>&nbsp;–</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.softomotive.com/the-2017-rpa-landscape-an-annual-review" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Softomotive RPA Landscape Annual Review</a></li><li>Prominence Of Chatbots80 percent of brands expect to serve customers through chatbots by 2020 –&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cms-connected.com/News-Archive/February-2018/Enterprises-Set-Themselves-Up-for-Success-via-Chatbots" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CMS Connected</a></li><li>Increasing Use Of Unstructured Data leads to RPA80 percent of worldwide data will be unstructured by 2025 –&nbsp;<a href="https://solutionsreview.com/data-management/80-percent-of-your-data-will-be-unstructured-in-five-years/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Solutions Review</a></li><li>Increased Automation Centers40 percent of organizations will set up automation centers and also heavily invest in centralized coordination centers or centers of excellence –&nbsp;<a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/automation-will-become-central-to-business-strategy-and-operations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ZDNet</a></li></ol>



<p>Lead RPA evangelist and AVP of Technology and Solutions at Cygnet Infotech,&nbsp;<a href="mailto:vivek.mishra@cygnetinfotech.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vivek Mishra</a>&nbsp;has a unique perception on RPA and has noted some vital reality checks to build a broader automation strategy. He firmly believes “RPA is a journey of optimizing repetitive tasks with the help of self-functioning automated bots”.</p>



<p>In his words- The Robotic Process Automation is increasing from just being a follower to now an optimizer of business processes. We are already living in a cyborg world where our dependency on technology is only going to increase. Hence, in the race of ‘survival of the fittest’ he strongly promotes RPA with an amalgamation of AI and Analytics. This will increase ROI and reduce operational cost on mundane and repetitive tasks.</p>



<h2>Achieve Automation Excellence with Cygnet Infotech’s RPA Capabilities</h2>



<p>Cygnet Infotech’s approach to digital transformation can help businesses to seamlessly optimize their processes and maximize their return on investment. We have successfully delivered intelligent RPA solutions aiding businesses to establish superior quality benchmarks.</p>



<p>As a recent success in the RPA space, Cygnet Infotech worked with a Pharma giant to automate its key business function.</p>



<p>Daily, huge amounts of data consumed significant time in data processing, as an aftermath, leading to erroneous outcome, inaccurate data and exposed mission critical operational inefficiency. Gauging these challenges, automation experts at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cygnet-infotech.com/success-stories/data-management-accuracy-increased-for-a-pharma-giant-with-rpa" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cygnet Infotech developed a Bot solution</a>&nbsp;capable of automating data processing and delivering accurate data. Cygnet Infotech’s RPA solution improved the data management accuracy by 99%, reduced the data processing time with improved ROI of almost 70%.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="975" height="599" src="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/rpa-solution-cygnet-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-33134" srcset="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/rpa-solution-cygnet-1.png 975w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/rpa-solution-cygnet-1-300x184.png 300w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/rpa-solution-cygnet-1-768x472.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 975px) 100vw, 975px" /></figure>



<h2>RPA Adoption : Survival of the Fittest</h2>



<p>The expansion of automation is happening at an unprecedented speed and most of businesses are exploring new ways to deal with this change. On the other hand, enterprises using RPA have reported multiple business benefits such as accelerated process time, improved efficiency and productivity and enhanced user experience.</p>



<p>As a Technology First company, Cygnet Infotech takes 100% agile approach to develop scalable RPA solutions that help businesses to harness the power of bots and cognitive automation within the enterprise.</p>



<p>Our experienced automation engineers are adept and innovative backed by their AI and analytics acumen that can help accelerate your digital transformation journey and help you to outsmart your competition.</p>The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/the-cios-take-on-rpa-optimize-business-processes-to-multiply-roi/">The CIO’s take on RPA: Optimize business processes to multiply ROI</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 RPA implementation challenges your business encounters and ways to overcome</title>
		<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/7-rpa-implementation-challenges-business-encounters-ways-to-overcome/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 11:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.automation-whiz.com/?p=33119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">5</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span> Content updated in April 2022 RPA (Robotic Process Automaton) enables businesses to leverage automation and enhance the performance and overall efficiency of the workforce by automating labor-intensive jobs and minimizing human errors. McKinsey Digital&#160;has found that RPA can result in an ROI between 30 and 200 percent in the first year. However, the road to&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/7-rpa-implementation-challenges-business-encounters-ways-to-overcome/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">7 RPA implementation challenges your business encounters and ways to overcome</span></a></p>
The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/7-rpa-implementation-challenges-business-encounters-ways-to-overcome/">7 RPA implementation challenges your business encounters and ways to overcome</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">5</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p><strong>Content updated in April 2022</strong></p>



<p>RPA (Robotic Process Automaton) enables businesses to leverage automation and enhance the performance and overall efficiency of the workforce by automating labor-intensive jobs and minimizing human errors.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/mckinsey-digital/our-insights/the-next-acronym-you-need-to-know-about-rpa" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">McKinsey Digital</a>&nbsp;has found that RPA can result in an ROI between 30 and 200 percent in the first year.</p>



<p>However, the road to RPA implementation is not an easy one. Infect, according to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ey.com/en_gl/digital/can-robots-help-your-business-be-more-human" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ernst and Young</a>, almost 50% of RPA project fail.</p>



<p>In this blog, we will discuss the 7 core challenges faced by the organizations in RPA implementation and methods via which they can resolve them:</p>



<h3>1. Employee resistance and its management&nbsp;</h3>



<p>A technological revolution of this magnitude does not go uncontested. This is a universal principle, and the case with the implementation of RPA is not an exception. The robots will steal our jobs, goes the common narrative. In this regard, the management’s understanding of the organization’s culture is tested.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>With Robotic Process Automation, we are talking about a digital workforce that can perform all the human resource functions, specifically rules-based and repetitive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For this, the management must take the existing workforce into confidence because embracing new technology is easier said than done.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>How to resolve</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CIOs would greatly favor the workforce by not being in a denial mode. They should come forward and explain that the implementation of RPA is likely to bring about a significant change in the landscape.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>A practical method to minimize change resistance is to involve all the employees in the early stage of RPA planning. Employees who are directly involved with a process know the nitty-gritty of the complete workflow.</p>



<p>Seeking responses and validation from people at all levels helps businesses build a realistic timeframe and processes for RPA implementation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Employees who feel valued show less resistance to the change. Moreover, the work hours vested in menial, repetitive tasks can now be invested in more creative activities such as customer service, strategizing sales, marketing, etc.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h3>2. Lack of clarity: what, how, where to implement RPA</h3>



<p>The RPA is not an end in itself; it is an enabler that enables organizations to do more with less, which can lead to greater productivity.</p>



<p>There are many challenges to implementing RPA, but one stands out: the lack of understanding of what RPA means. Most people think RPA is just automation or robots doing repetitive tasks. But this is only a part of the entire story. In reality, RPA is much broader than that, it’s about automating the entire business process.</p>



<p><strong>There are three main types of RPA:</strong>&nbsp;robotic process automation, cognitive computing, and conversational computing. Each type uses different technologies to automate processes.</p>



<p>For example:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Robotic process automation</strong>&nbsp;uses machine learning algorithms to perform simple data entry or email routing tasks.</li><li><strong>Cognitive computing</strong>&nbsp;uses natural language processing to interpret user requests and provide automated responses.</li><li><strong>Conversational computing</strong>&nbsp;uses speech recognition and text-to-speech synthesis to allow humans to interact with machines.</li></ul>



<p><strong>How to resolve<br></strong><br>Automation is an important part of any business process. It helps businesses to reduce costs and increase productivity. However, automation cannot replace human intelligence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Certain best practices need to be followed during the RPA implementation process to ensure that a business process is completely automated. These include:</p>



<ul><li>There must be a proper understanding of how the business process works.&nbsp;</li><li>A good design for the entire business workflow needs to be created.</li><li>Right automated tool should be adopted to effectuate RPA implementation &nbsp;</li><li>Business users must be involved at every step of the way.</li><li>The business process must be tested thoroughly before it can be deployed into production.</li><li>Complete visibility into how RPA will impact all aspects of business, including finances, inventory, sales, marketing, customer services, and human resources should be penned down.</li></ul>



<h3>3. The security risks assessment</h3>



<p>Implementing RPA solutions means granting access to all your legacy systems like CRM, ERP, accounting software, etc. The bot will handle a large chunk of data to execute any rules-based task.</p>



<p>In a scenario like this, there are high chances of data misuse, either in employee mistakes or cyber-attacks by hackers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The main security risks related to RPA are cyber-attacks against the software itself, which could compromise its integrity and functionality. In addition, it is important to consider the possibility of malicious users gaining access to the system through social engineering attacks, phishing emails, and many more.</p>



<p><strong>How to resolve:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>A sub-team within the RPA team can be employed to monitor and report any bot misbehavior.</li><li>Active directory integration and encryption are other complementary measures that can be taken to prevent any security breach.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>To mitigate this risk associated with sensitive data, organizations should implement robust authentication methods and encrypt all sensitive data.</li><li>The leading challenge for organizations implementing RPA is the lack of visibility into the execution of tasks and the ability to detect anomalies. This makes it challenging to identify and resolve issues before they become serious problems.&nbsp;</li><li>Organizations must ensure that the automation solution has built-in mechanisms to monitor the execution of tasks and alert users if any errors occur.</li></ul>



<h3>4. Tackling the total cost of ownership</h3>



<p>According to a&nbsp;<a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/content/dam/Deloitte/us/Documents/process-and-operations/us-cons-global-rpa-survey.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">survey</a>, out of 500 respondents employing a wide range of RPA solutions across various industries globally, 41% of the respondents said it is difficult to maintain RPA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As more companies embrace digital transformation by employing RPA, one of the biggest challenges is the TCO (Total Cost of Ownership). And it why because software and hardware costs are important components of TCO.</p>



<p>The software costs mainly include operating system costs, bot licenses, Virtual machines, etc. Whereas hardware costs include machines, servers, databases, and alike.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>How to resolve</strong></p>



<ul><li>Multithreading for data processing is one option that can be applied by highly data-intensive organizations which are stored at several places. By multithreading, the RPA tool can reduce the turnaround time up to 1000 times faster.</li><li>Running multiple RPA bots (6-8) on a single virtual machine also reduces the overall costs of operating system and hardware licenses.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h3>5. Choice of correct processes for automation</h3>



<p>To get started with RPA, “you have to pick the right process. It has to be stable, mature, optimized, rules-based, repetitive, and usually high-volume,” said Leslie Willcocks, professor of technology, work, and globalization at the London School of Economics, in a discussion with&nbsp;<em>McKinsey</em>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The bots are ready, are you?” – Goes the saying across the industry when the question of adopting RPA arises. Irrespective of the size of your organization, the decision to adopt and deploy RPA is one major challenge.</p>



<p><strong>How to resolve&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is easier to automate template-driven processes where decision-making is based on standardized and predictive rules.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>RPA can be deployed for processes with readable input such as text-based data, user interface (UI) activities like keyboard strokes, mouse clicks, etc., optical character recognition, and green screen.&nbsp;</li><li>Big-sized batches that don’t require intrinsic knowledge should be automated to bring an immediate boost to the employees’ efficiency&nbsp;</li><li>Processes that need to comply with the safety and quality norms should be ideally automated.</li><li>Repeated customer queries that need quicker resolution and fast settlement should be considered for automation by employing chatbots&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h3>6. Challenges of scaling up</h3>



<p>Though the early adoption rate for RPA may seem encouraging, only 3% of organizations have scaled their digital workforce according to&nbsp;<a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/ro/en/pages/technology-media-and-telecommunications/articles/deloitte-global-rpa-survey.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Deloitte Global RPA Survey</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This gap is substantial for a solution that boasts of saving time and costs.</p>



<p><strong>How to&nbsp;</strong><strong>resolve</strong></p>



<ul><li>In the given scenario, developers have proposed models such as robot-as-a-service or&nbsp;<em>RaaS</em>. This will allow new customers embarking on digital projects to scale up quickly by obtaining licenses, implementing platforms, and placing the RPA application on the platform.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Optimizing processes before automating. One of the best approaches to ensure scalability is fixing existing processes by identifying patterns and optimizing them by involving every stakeholder.&nbsp;</li><li>Businesses that leverage the collective expertise of the involved stakeholders are likely to optimize process selection, enhancing scalability.</li></ul>



<h3>7. Preparing for the C-Suite</h3>



<p>Implementing an enterprise-wide digital workforce requires the support and sponsorship of the c-suite because the cost-benefit analysis drives the c-suite. The C-suite will not approve of any automation initiatives unless sustained and tangible benefits are visible to them accruing in the foreseeable future.</p>



<p><strong>How to resolve</strong><br><br>On-boarding the C-suite and functional leadership with a plan of action backed by cost-benefit analysis in the near to medium term will be an ideal approach to implementing RPA.</p>



<h2>Conclusion:</h2>



<p>There are many challenges to any transformation project and RPA implementations are no different. The key issues you must consider above all are: leadership and communication.</p>



<p>Without leadership (without C-suite sponsorship), the adoption rate of RPA and AI will be too slow to be of any real benefit to the company. And without communication, the benefits that accrue from RPA will not be heard or seen by all those who can benefit.</p>



<p>To tap the capabilities of RPA and accelerate your digital transformation journey, you can talk to our automation experts from&nbsp;<a href="https://automationwhiz.store/home" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AutomationwhiZ</a>.</p>The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/7-rpa-implementation-challenges-business-encounters-ways-to-overcome/">7 RPA implementation challenges your business encounters and ways to overcome</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quick Guide: Common business processes best suited for Robotic Process Automation</title>
		<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/quick-guide-common-business-processes-best-suited-for-robotic-process-automation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.automation-whiz.com/?p=33097</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span> There’s a lot of automation that can happen that isn’t a replacement of humans but of mind-numbing behavior.” -Stewart Butterfield Robotic Process Automation is revolutionalizing the business workflow. Its adoption streamlines business processes, reduces human efforts &#38; errors, shifts focus on valuable and rewarding aspects of work, delivers better output rapidly, and enhances the efficiency&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/quick-guide-common-business-processes-best-suited-for-robotic-process-automation/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Quick Guide: Common business processes best suited for Robotic Process Automation</span></a></p>
The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/quick-guide-common-business-processes-best-suited-for-robotic-process-automation/">Quick Guide: Common business processes best suited for Robotic Process Automation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>There’s a lot of automation that can happen that isn’t a replacement of humans but of mind-numbing behavior.” -Stewart Butterfield</p></blockquote>



<p>Robotic Process Automation is revolutionalizing the business workflow. Its adoption streamlines business processes, reduces human efforts &amp; errors, shifts focus on valuable and rewarding aspects of work, delivers better output rapidly, and enhances the efficiency of the workforce.</p>



<p>Recently global IT research and advisory firms like&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2019-06-24-gartner-says-worldwide-robotic-process-automation-sof" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gartner declared RPA as the fastest-growing segment</a>&nbsp;in the worldwide enterprise software market. However, many businesses are still unaware of the positive impact of virtual workforce capabilities and opportunities. The challenges that they face are –</p>



<ul><li>What are the processes that are well-suited for automation?</li><li>How to identify the right business operation for RPA adoption??</li></ul>



<p>If your business is struggling with the same questions, check out the most common business operations suitable for RPA.</p>



<h2>Workforce Dependent Processes</h2>



<p>&nbsp;According to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.smartsheet.com/content-center/product-news/automation/workers-waste-quarter-work-week-manual-repetitive-tasks" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a report published by Smartsheet</a>, more than 40% of respondents said they spend at least a quarter of their workweek on manual, repetitive tasks, with email, data collection, and data entry occupying the most time.</p>



<p>These scenarios are quite common in the business world where the employees perform tedious and monotonous work every day. Such functions waste their time and affect the overall efficiency and productivity.</p>



<p>For instance- in financial institutes, customer onboarding becomes a nerve-wracking experience, for employees dealing with a large number of prospects and clients every day.&nbsp;The processes include-</p>



<ul><li>long trails of paperwork</li><li>extensive documentation</li><li>tedious approvals causing delays</li><li>identity verification processes, and more</li></ul>



<p>RPA is the sign of relief for such employees and also a great way to deliver improved customer experience.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Process with less human intervention</h2>



<p>How will you feel if you listen to the same problems from multiple people every day?</p>



<p>Tech support employees have to listen about the same problem from multiple people and repeat the similar process to fix similar system failures every day. Also, they are always extra loaded with work. So, what is the easy way out? RPA is the answer!</p>



<p>Such diagnostic processes need limited end-to-end human intervention.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cygnet-infotech.com/ebooks/handbook-to-expand-your-automation-footprint-with-rpa" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Getting started with RPA</a>&nbsp;can streamline their workflow and free the support staff from anxiety and stress so that they can focus better on priorities.</p>



<h2>High volume work</h2>



<p>One of the key findings of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/ro/en/pages/technology-media-and-telecommunications/articles/deloitte-global-rpa-survey.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Deloitte Global RPA Survey</a>&nbsp;states that&nbsp;53% of their respondents started to implement some form of RPA, and this percentage will become 72% by 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many times, the high volume of work becomes overwhelming for the businesses.&nbsp;Some businesses run round the clock with no opening and closing times. The retail sector can be the best example where the business deals with-</p>



<ul><li>High volume of orders everyday/week</li><li>Inventory management</li><li>Complaint resolutions</li><li>Generating sales reports</li></ul>



<p>RPA implements these and other operations rapidly and accurately helping businesses save hours of work, efforts, and costs.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Rule-based processes</h2>



<p><a href="https://fr.majorel.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Arvato_Whitepaper-Impact-of-RPA-on-finance-back-office-processes.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">A recent study by A.T. Kearney and Arvato</a>&nbsp;reveals RPA will take over 41 percent of the financial back-office processes and in ten years, it will be 53 percent.</p>



<p>But the truth is, RPA can disrupt not only the back-office functions but also the front office business operations. However, bots are popular in obeying well-defined rules in data-driven processes; the businesses are a little more in favor of adopting automation for back offices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For instance- in the telecom business, operations that include:</p>



<ul><li>Allotting new SIM to customers</li><li>Porting numbers to other operators</li><li>Customer conflict resolution</li><li>Credit checks for post-paid accounts</li></ul>



<p>Some of these transactions can be easily and efficiently automated, lessen the burden of work and enhance customer satisfaction.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>“Automation is good, so long as you know exactly where to put the machine.” ~&nbsp;Eliyahu Goldratt.</p></blockquote>



<p>This quote briefly explains the need for identifying legacy business processes that can be automated, to reap the benefits of cognitive and artificial intelligence technologies. It will help the businesses to shift from redundant, low-skilled, rule-based business operations to critical engagements. Such transformations will help the businesses in delivering value, increasing revenue, and building healthier relationships with clients and customers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tap the capabilities of RPA and accelerate your digital transformation journey with our automation engineers from AutomationwhiZ. Get in touch with our experts now, at <a href="mailto:info@automation-whiz.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">info@automation-whiz.com</a>.</p>The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/quick-guide-common-business-processes-best-suited-for-robotic-process-automation/">Quick Guide: Common business processes best suited for Robotic Process Automation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How RPA ensures business resiliency during Covid19</title>
		<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/how-rpa-ensures-business-resiliency-during-covid19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.automation-whiz.com/?p=33125</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span> Hit by COVID-19, separated by social distancing and under national lockdown triggered an economic downturn. The operational resilience of every industry is tested like never before – urging Industry leaders to respond to a drastic shift in demand. Only 12% of organizations are highly prepared for coronavirus. –&#160;Gartner Organizations are often ill-prepared to react to&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/how-rpa-ensures-business-resiliency-during-covid19/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">How RPA ensures business resiliency during Covid19</span></a></p>
The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/how-rpa-ensures-business-resiliency-during-covid19/">How RPA ensures business resiliency during Covid19</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>Hit by COVID-19, separated by social distancing and under national lockdown triggered an economic downturn. The operational resilience of every industry is tested like never before – urging Industry leaders to respond to a drastic shift in demand.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Only 12% of organizations are highly prepared for coronavirus. –&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2020-03-10-gartner-business-continuity-survey-shows-just-twelve-percernt-of-organizations-are-highly-prepared-for-coronavirsu" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gartner</a></p></blockquote>



<p>Organizations are often ill-prepared to react to such sudden emerging risks. As priorities shift, business leaders will have to reshape their strategy several times to address the business implications facing each industry.</p>



<p>Unforeseen challenges such as business continuity risks, workforce productivity loss, security risks – all this need immediate attention encouraging leaders to adopt robotic process automation at an alarming pace.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/achieve-sustainable-success-with-rpa-driven-digital-transformation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RPA can bring digital transformation</a> in the areas of operational efficiency and consumer engagement by automating a bulk of business processes.</p>



<h2>Role of RPA in the COVID-19 battle</h2>



<p>RPA is a beacon of hope to keep business and service levels afloat. &nbsp;With work from home becoming the de facto norm, employees face difficulty in conducting several virtual meetings, calls, and record minutes of the meeting. &nbsp;To ease this transition, smart MOM BOTs that can take any audio/video recorded file and convert speech to text in a structured format in an output document file can be implemented.</p>



<p>From managing high volumes of testing results and processing a large volume of claims to supporting the increased need for customer service and empowering remote workforce, RPA allows businesses to sustain the operations.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="850" height="520" src="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/automation-on-increase-in-covid-19.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-33126" srcset="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/automation-on-increase-in-covid-19.jpg 850w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/automation-on-increase-in-covid-19-300x184.jpg 300w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/automation-on-increase-in-covid-19-768x470.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></figure>



<p>Robotic Process Automation (RPA) has a proven record of being a vital tool to navigate the current global crisis. With bots being deployed in business processes, it is easier for organizations to tackle rising challenges caused by COVID-19.</p>



<h2>Before &amp; After RPA: Exploring the possibilities</h2>



<p>Take, for instance, a typical banking process that relied on walk-ins for account opening, and manual process of filling forms are now forced to work with restricted workforce or completely shut down branches resulting in a sharp decline in providing customer service.</p>



<p>Hence, there is no better option for businesses to leverage RPA as a preventive measure for business continuity.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="850" height="440" src="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/covid-automation-before-and-after.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-33127" srcset="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/covid-automation-before-and-after.jpg 850w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/covid-automation-before-and-after-300x155.jpg 300w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/covid-automation-before-and-after-768x398.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></figure>



<p>With automation in place, data capturing, verification, and approval of the KYC process hardly take a few minutes. The entire mechanism operates in a streamlined manner.</p>



<p>Banks are also deploying customer-facing bots – including Chatbots or Voice bots to ensure that there are no customer complaints left unaddressed whether they are related to unmatched balances, incorrect charges, or other similar issues. Automating the account opening process can improve processing speed, reduce operating costs, and reliance on FTEs/agents.</p>



<p>RPA is at the forefront to flatten the COVID-19 curve by stepping up and providing innovative solutions. Right from Healthcare to the adversely impacted industries such as Travel &amp; Hospitality, Pharmaceuticals, HR, Supply chain and Financial Services and Insurance (BFSI) – automation is finding its way across industries.</p>



<p>Some of the use cases of RPA include:</p>



<h5><strong>Healthcare</strong></h5>



<ul><li>Accelerate COVID-19 Testing &amp; Reduce Wait Times</li><li>Accelerate Patient Diagnosis for COVID-19</li><li>Schedule Remote Patient Consultations 24/7</li><li>Health Screening Bots for Monitoring Employee Health</li><li>Contact Center Support to Manage Queries</li></ul>



<h5><strong>Travel &amp; Hospitality</strong></h5>



<ul><li>Self-Management of Flight Disruptions</li><li>Chatbots for Updating and Communicating with Travelers</li><li>Detecting Travelers Suspected of COVID-19</li><li>Crew Scheduling for Restricted Travel</li></ul>



<h5><strong>Human Resource</strong></h5>



<ul><li>Automate employee onboarding process</li><li>Automate emails with a structured report to the stakeholders.</li><li>Employee Data Management.</li></ul>



<h5><strong>Supply Chain</strong></h5>



<ul><li>Automate Shipment Scheduling and Tracking</li><li>Speed Invoicing by Integrating Systems with Customer Portals</li><li>Automate Order/Inventory Tracking</li><li>Improve Forecasting and Logistics Planning</li></ul>



<p>RPA foster a feeling of camaraderie to remote employees in tough times and keeps businesses operationally agile.</p>



<p>One of the most powerful benefits of RPA is&nbsp;<strong>reliability</strong>: The bot can tirelessly work&nbsp;<strong>24 hours&nbsp;</strong>for&nbsp;<strong>365 days&nbsp;</strong>with nearly&nbsp;<strong>100%&nbsp;</strong>accuracy and without interruption.” It is non-invasive in nature and promises to reduce turnaround times, lower operating costs, improved compliance, and higher customer satisfaction.</p>



<h2>How Cygnet Infotech’s RPA capabilities ensures business continuity</h2>



<p>The coronavirus pandemic is likely to strain every business for the foreseeable future. You need a catalyst that accelerates your RPA adoption with a holistic approach to survive in the global economic meltdown.</p>



<p>At Cygnet Infotech, we advocate a new way to deploy RPA—what we call our ‘Technology&nbsp;First’ approach to augments the digital operations of organizations of tomorrow, radically reducing handling time while providing superior user and customer experience.</p>



<p>Cygnet Infotech has been leading from the front against the fight with COVID-19 by intelligent RPA solutions. Our expert tech architects provided&nbsp;a robust RPA solution&nbsp;to one of the leading pharma companies that had been facing a major challenge in identifying and manually managing the entire customer data. The solution ultimately fast-tracked the client’s&nbsp;<strong>productivity by 40%</strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong>achieved 99% accuracy</strong>&nbsp;using the Bot to mimic human actions while performing the task.</p>



<p>So, why wait for the storm to come and disrupt, adopt RPA technology to drive business continuity, maintain process efficiencies, and amplify customer experience.</p>The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/how-rpa-ensures-business-resiliency-during-covid19/">How RPA ensures business resiliency during Covid19</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Six key checkpoints to master the knack of RPA implementation</title>
		<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/six-key-checkpoints-to-master-the-knack-of-rpa-implementation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 09:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.automation-whiz.com/?p=33151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span> Gartner predicts that by 2020, end-user spending on robotic process automation software is set to reach $1 billion. Digital disruption and the changing nature of customer preferences have made it imperative for traditional businesses to reinvent their tectonic business processes. In this pursuit, robotic process automation acquires the driver’s seat. RPA has the potential to&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/six-key-checkpoints-to-master-the-knack-of-rpa-implementation/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Six key checkpoints to master the knack of RPA implementation</span></a></p>
The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/six-key-checkpoints-to-master-the-knack-of-rpa-implementation/">Six key checkpoints to master the knack of RPA implementation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Gartner predicts that by 2020, end-user spending on robotic process automation software is set to reach $1 billion.</p></blockquote>



<p>Digital disruption and the changing nature of customer preferences have made it imperative for traditional businesses to reinvent their tectonic business processes. In this pursuit, robotic process automation acquires the driver’s seat.</p>



<p>RPA has the potential to address “digital gaps” in any business. It automates manual processes and infuses agility. It can empower the frontline staff to focus on other value-added tasks by automating “long-tail” of low-volume or low-value processes.</p>



<p>Businesses process across several industries such as Human Resource, Logistics, Finance, Supply Chain, Manufacturing, Customer Support, and others are leveraging RPA to reduce costs, slash processing time and outrival competitors.</p>



<p>Although many organizations have adopted some level of RPA, many processes still fall through the cracks. The reason could be legacy systems, a melange of traditional practices, cost of integrating systems and lack of governance in business processes.</p>



<p>In the previous article, we already understood the true transformative power of RPA to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/achieve-sustainable-success-with-rpa-driven-digital-transformation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">achieve sustainable success with RPA driven digital transformation</a>. Yet, getting the best out of RPA adoption requires a carefully crafted strategy and best practices to achieve automation at scale.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>“RPA is a technology that is easy to use, but things take time, and so does an RPA implementation. A sound foundation must be created for the purpose of further scaling, and this requires a solid basis with a defined strategy, communication plans and change management, trained RPA experts and a stable IT infrastructure – just to mention some examples.” – Zeeshan Rajan, Senior Manager, PwC</p></blockquote>



<h3><strong>Cygnet Infotech outlines these six best practices that businesses should consider while banking on RPA.</strong></h3>



<h4>Creating the RPA Centre of Excellence</h4>



<p>A Center of Excellence (CoE) is essential to embed RPA strategically and effectively into the organization. It is essential to define a robotic operating team with a set of clearly defined roles and responsibilities for all business functions. In addition, a configured and fine-tuned development environment is crucial to run, manage and implement automation efficiently throughout the enterprise. RPA Center of Excellence must lay down and monitor key performance indicators and should get the best out of bots.</p>



<h4>Select the Right Process for Automation</h4>



<p>Certain business processes may require cognitive automation, while others need standalone automation. However, processes that require high manual intervention are the best candidates for automation.</p>



<h5>Following processes are ideal for RPA implementation.</h5>



<ul><li><strong>Labour-intensive:</strong>&nbsp;Processes that require a high number of employees</li><li><strong>Rule-based:</strong>&nbsp;Processes driven by simple rules &amp; logic with minimal exceptions</li><li><strong>Standardized/structured data:</strong>&nbsp;RPA tools can process standardized, structured, and digitized data</li><li><strong>Data-entry workflow processes:</strong>&nbsp;Entering data from claims documents into a claims management system and invoice-processing functions</li><li><strong>Data extraction from standard databases:</strong>&nbsp;For example – extracting customer information to file tax claims and data migration activities from one system to another</li><li><strong>Routine processes:</strong>&nbsp;Insurance claims processing and banking transactions</li></ul>



<p>Process assessment is an ongoing activity to identify more opportunities for automation through RPA.</p>



<h4>Gain IT Buy-In</h4>



<p>It is essential to have an expert technology partner on your side to integrate RPA solutions successfully. Reason being, security, scalability, bot implementation, quality assurance, incident management and effective training for user acceptance. Although, RPA is process friendly, an agile IT partner having digital mindset can help you seamlessly navigate through the RPA adoption journey.</p>



<p>At Cygnet, we advocate a new method of deploying RPA— we call it the ‘Technology-first’ approach. Our expert tech-architects democratize RPA solutions with a scalable architecture that augments digital operations and reduces handling time while providing superior user experience.</p>



<h4>Design and Deploy First Use Case</h4>



<p>Each RPA journey is unique. Before considering an enterprise-wide scope, deploy your first use case within a small functional area where automation can extract the expected value. Then roll out RPA step-by-step to other parts of the organization. Measure the success of your first use case to build interest in implementing RPA across the organization.</p>



<h4>Ensuring Right Governance for Automation at Scale</h4>



<p>Enterprises need to establish an automation governance mechanism to ensure that robotic processes comply with regulatory controls and standards. While defining the governance structure, it is important to understand the organization’s value chain to ensure RPA will enhance the end-to-end flow of value. To implement governance carefully and correctly, an agile approach with the right leadership can drive high-velocity RPA implementation.</p>



<h4>Robotics Require A Transformation Program</h4>



<p>Organizations achieving scale in RPA implementation need to recognize the potential of adopting approaches and techniques associated with large-scale change programs. Moving beyond the evaluation stage to RPA transformation leads to the development or acquisition of new skills. To fully leverage the potential of robots and cognitive automation, businesses need to augment their workforce to build internal RPA-delivery capability and enable them to deliver high-value performance.</p>



<p>At Cygnet Infotech, our automation engineers and process analysts have deep domain knowledge and high-velocity engineering prowess to develop RPA solutions with scalable architecture and a 100% agile approach. We have already delivered 55+ software bots that are saving a significant number of man-hours for clients. Contact us to find out which bot best fits your business process.</p>The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/six-key-checkpoints-to-master-the-knack-of-rpa-implementation/">Six key checkpoints to master the knack of RPA implementation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Achieve sustainable success with RPA driven Digital Transformation</title>
		<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/achieve-sustainable-success-with-rpa-driven-digital-transformation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 12:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.automation-whiz.com/?p=33269</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span> The unbridled enthusiasm for digital transformation has prompted enterprises to storyboard roadmap to embrace the next wave of technology. The pace at which technology is mushrooming around, enterprises are in the dire need of automating labor-intensive business processes. This is where Robotic Process Automation-led digital transformation has acquired the center stage. RPA successfully replicates human&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/achieve-sustainable-success-with-rpa-driven-digital-transformation/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Achieve sustainable success with RPA driven Digital Transformation</span></a></p>
The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/achieve-sustainable-success-with-rpa-driven-digital-transformation/">Achieve sustainable success with RPA driven Digital Transformation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>The unbridled enthusiasm for digital transformation has prompted enterprises to storyboard roadmap to embrace the next wave of technology. The pace at which technology is mushrooming around, enterprises are in the dire need of automating labor-intensive business processes. This is where Robotic Process Automation-led digital transformation has acquired the center stage.</p>



<p>RPA successfully replicates human actions to handle heaps of repetitive tasks that normally involves multiple human resources fully engrossed in completing them without adding noticeable business value.</p>



<p>Needless to mention AI, machine learning and other technologies have emerged on the scene to make this happen, and yet Robotic Process Automation has proved to be impactful as it can smartly mimic human actions and perform mundane technical tasks and thereby evolving workforce to perform other high-value tasks. It can quickly fix perpetual legacy system problems such as integration, migration and information sharing issues leaving fragmented customer experience behind.</p>



<p>While many companies are thriving in this environment and disrupting their status quo, countless heads are still on the lookout to realize their true transformative power.</p>



<h2>Robotic Process Automation – The Need of The Hour</h2>



<p>Automation is the tip of the digital transformation iceberg that is impacting everything from customer experience and company infrastructure to business operations and outcomes.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>As per the estimates, the adoption rate of Robotic Process Automation across organizations is growing at a lightning speed and it will be a $1.5 billion&nbsp;business by 2020.&nbsp;–&nbsp;<a href="https://go.forrester.com/blogs/predictions-2019-automation-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Forrester</strong></a>.</p></blockquote>



<p>RPA can automate manual processes, increase production, ease software bots deployment, minimize human errors, boost employee energy levels and productivity that has exponentially fueled its growth.</p>



<p>On the other hand, digital transformation reflects in a way the enterprise systems have evolved over the years such as:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Enterprise Applications (1980’s)</strong>: Streamlined core business processes to scale operations. However, lack of integration resulted in functional silos.</li><li><strong>Business Process Management (BPM) (Late 1990’s)</strong>: Integrated and harmonized processes across various applications using analytics and process management methods. To achieve continuous performance improvement, it required huge cost and workforce skill.</li><li><strong>Digital Process Automation (DPA) (2010’s)</strong>: Next-generation BPM extended the reach of process automation to address long-tail business needs by leveraging API-based development with an agile approach to integrate RPA into enterprise workflow.</li></ul>



<p>All these years, RPA has proved its potential in various operational functions such as human resources, logistics, finance, supply chain, manufacturing and customer support.</p>



<p>Apart from this, <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/quick-guide-to-robotic-process-automation-for-business" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RPA has helped enterprises taste success</a> in handling rule-based tasks such as onboarding, complaints handling and reporting.</p>



<h2>Some of the use cases where RPA proves its value:</h2>



<ul><li><strong>Vendor, Customer and Employee Onboarding</strong>: These processes span across finance &amp; accounting, sales/new accounts and HR and often involve reams of paperwork, vetting, and lengthy back-and-forth manual processes that naturally lend themselves to automation. RPA helps to entirely automate the onboarding process including full data integration with internal systems and automatic status communication.</li><li><strong>Payroll Processing</strong>: Varying tax laws, changing report requirements and simply working with disparate systems can fizzle out your payroll processing. RPA can automate the gathering and synchronizing data with multiple systems such as HR, accounts payable, ledger entries and employees to provide accounting reports in a fraction of time; leaving required bandwidth and brainpower to leverage that information for valuable insights.</li><li><strong>Customer Support</strong>: Various repetitive and tedious tasks of solving immediate, round-the-clock customer queries needs automation. RPA can automatically diagnose and troubleshoot technical problems, track support tickets and even provide minor issue resolution to customer – delivering a people-centric service.</li></ul>



<p>These are just some of the processes that RPA dramatically automates across various industries, significantly reducing dependency on costly labor and increasing service efficiency.</p>



<p>It’s this need that is leading to a surge of interest in Robotic Process Automation (RPA). Besides, to reap the benefit of faster time to value, you need a catalyst that accelerates your RPA adoption.</p>



<p>At Cygnet Infotech, we advocate a new way to deploy RPA—what we call our ‘Technology First’ approach. The key is to democratize RPA solutions with a scalable architecture that efficiently augments digital operations radically reducing handling time while providing superior user and customer experience.</p>



<p>In practice, even though RPA technology provides the foundation for significant competitive advantage, it is considered as one part of the holistic automation approach.</p>



<h2>RPA and DPA Convergence</h2>



<p>In a broader view, where RPA is another weapon in the fight against manual, repetitive and administrative work, DPA (Digital Process Automation) augments RPA, using a range of automation technologies taking a more strategic approach toward automation to improve the customer experience.</p>



<p>A DPA strategy aims to fulfill the advanced needs of the enterprises by leveraging Big Data and AI capabilities along with RPA. Combination of these technologies can act as a guided support to understand business patterns and performance of their workflow. Companies can then utilize this information to reimagine and digitize end-to-end processes that truly meet the needs of modern customers.</p>



<p>While RPA and DPA are fundamentally different approaches to support comprehensive, end-to-end process automation, in combination, they create a powerful digital transformation strategy. However, transformation isn’t plug and play. You need to apply design thinking to redefine existing processes and foster your business growth keeping customers at the center. It’s all about human centric designs and experiences.</p>



<p>Many companies are achieving superior business process optimization with Cygnet Infotech’s intelligent RPA solutions that are developed through a 100% agile approach. Our intelligent tech architects develop a scalable architecture allowing you to accelerate business outcomes.</p>The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/achieve-sustainable-success-with-rpa-driven-digital-transformation/">Achieve sustainable success with RPA driven Digital Transformation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Understanding the Role of RPA in Test Automation</title>
		<link>https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/understanding-the-role-of-rpa-in-test-automation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.automation-whiz.com/?p=33261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">4</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span> In this world of digitalization, new technologies keep up and coming in the market. A variety of emerging technologies have already received quite a lot of buzz. In order to keep up with the rapid pace of their competitors, businesses are trying to adopt and accept the ongoing trends in the market. The emergence of&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/understanding-the-role-of-rpa-in-test-automation/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Understanding the Role of RPA in Test Automation</span></a></p>
The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/understanding-the-role-of-rpa-in-test-automation/">Understanding the Role of RPA in Test Automation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">4</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>In this world of digitalization, new technologies keep up and coming in the market. A variety of emerging technologies have already received quite a lot of buzz. In order to keep up with the rapid pace of their competitors, businesses are trying to adopt and accept the ongoing trends in the market.</p>



<p>The emergence of sophisticated Artificial Intelligence has garnered much attention both online and offline. It has made machines learn and interpret humans while leaving a small room for errors.</p>



<p>Artificial intelligence and Machine Learning power the automation of repetitive and mundane processes. Robotic Process Automation (RPA) is one of the several ways AI and ML can make businesses achieve their goals. Here we attempt to dissect just how RPA can boost business growth.</p>



<p>Robotic Process Automation features new technology methods which structure and automate business processes. It is cost-effective, quick and reliable. RPA automates the routine, repetitive, time consuming and rule-based tasks using Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning without human intervention.</p>



<p>Unlike common misconceptions, RPA doesn’t use actual robots that replace human beings, instead RPA is the process of using software for automation of business operations.</p>



<p>It is used in sectors like healthcare, accounting, human resources, supply chain management and much more.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><a href="https://www.cgi.com/en/automation/rpa" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">CGI Report</a> suggests that nearly 20%–50% process cost reduction can take place with 15% greater transaction throughput capacity and 20% improved quality, reduced error rates and process variation.</p></blockquote>



<p>The RPA tool is an excellent benefit for testers. It begins its work by first undergoing codeless automation macros on desktop. In fact, it serves as a time saver.</p>



<p>When it comes to the testing pyramid, GUI testing is relatively more expensive compared to unit and integration testing and hence performed less. Using RPA tools for testing, GUI testing can be easily performed in shorter duration as these tools can capture repeated processes.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="843" height="563" src="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/rpa_gui_testing.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-33264" srcset="https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/rpa_gui_testing.jpg 843w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/rpa_gui_testing-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.automation-whiz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/rpa_gui_testing-768x513.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 843px) 100vw, 843px" /></figure>



<p>RPA is becoming a trend in the business fraternity, and why not, considering the several advantages it offers.</p>



<h2>Robotic Process Automation for Business</h2>



<p>Business users have to routinely interact with multiple systems on a regular basis. That’s where RPA steps in by automating these processes while saving time and minimizing additional spend on the resources needed for maintenance.</p>



<p>For instance, when a company hires an employee, his details get stored in a directory. The HR department then takes care of all the processes and registers him in the company’s database. Depending on the industry and nature of the business, this can easily take at least one working day, if not more.</p>



<p>Using RPA, the same can be performed much faster with higher accuracy usually in minutes. That’s why companies are automating processes swiftly as the first step of Digital Transformation.</p>



<p>RPA serves some key functions that make the testing process faster and more accurate.</p>



<h2>Here are some keys points that RPA implements:</h2>



<ol><li>Understanding the Automated ProcessWhen automating the process, it tends to undergo many changes. The first step for the testing team is to understand the automated process as the strategic approach is built methodically based on this initial step.</li><li>Verifying the AutomationThe automation can be verified by cross checking it with the existing business rules. The test scenarios should be concise and clear.</li><li>Test casesThe test cases have these columns – input data, actual results, exceptions and valid or invalid. This helps cover a variety of scenarios.</li><li>Testing the dataThe most important part of testing is the data. If the data is inaccurate, the results generated will generate errors.</li><li>Managing ErrorsThe defects acknowledged during the testing should be listed and notified to the development team.</li></ol>



<p>After understanding, five ways RPA works for testing, let’s see why it’s a win-win for businesses to utilize it.</p>



<h2>Features of RPA Testing</h2>



<ul><li>It is codeless so there is no need of memorizing the syntax.</li><li>Creating a process is convenient with drag and drop options.</li><li>It is scalable and accurate.</li><li>It is cost saving as minimal workforce is used.</li><li>It is accurate as the tasks are performed by automated processes.</li></ul>



<p>RPA often gets confused with Test Automation. But, is RPA testing actually the same as Test Automation?</p>



<p>There are quite a few differences between RPA testing and Test Automation. Here is a short list of the differences between the two.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><th>Test Automation</th><th>RPA Testing</th></tr><tr><td>The goal of automation is reduction in the test execution time.</td><td>The goal of RPA is reduction in the headcount.</td></tr><tr><td>It automates repetitive test cases.</td><td>It automates repetitive business processes.</td></tr><tr><td>It requires coding knowledge.</td><td>It is codeless and wizard driven.</td></tr><tr><td>Acts as virtual assistance.</td><td>Acts as virtual workforce.</td></tr><tr><td>It automates only the product.</td><td>It automates both product and services.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Test automation has made the process of testing easier and accurate but the introduction of RPA in testing has improved the work efficiency of repetitive tasks.</p>



<h2>RPA has several advantages for businesses including:</h2>



<ol><li><strong>Saving Time</strong><br>It is cost – time efficient and increase throughput.</li><li><strong>Higher Productivity</strong><br>It allows employees to invest their time in productive work as the retentive and mundane tasks are performed by robots.</li><li><strong>Increased ROI</strong><br>It expands virtual force quickly by minimizing manual work, providing error free output with higher return on investment.</li><li><strong>Accurate Results</strong><br>It eliminates human errors improving customer satisfaction.</li></ol>



<p>RPA has taken the test automation process to the next level. With RPA the process of testing has become codeless, accurate, easy and flexible.</p>



<p>If you are considering implementing RPA testing in your Organization, you have come to the right place. The Cygnet Advantage guarantees you get 100% agile, adaptable and flexible technology solutions for your organization.</p>The post <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com/blog/understanding-the-role-of-rpa-in-test-automation/">Understanding the Role of RPA in Test Automation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.automation-whiz.com">AutomationWhiz</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
